Nicoletta Nutrito

Phone 00 39 3517734512

e-mail: nicoletta.nutrito@novastone-ca.com

I am an engineer with a passion for travels and sports. I was born and raised in Bologna, Italy and in the past 20 years I raised through the ranks in global companies.

Expert in Supply Chain, Manufacturing, and digital transformation.

I can motivate a team, manage a P&L and leverage new technologies to enhance existing product and services.

At this point in my career, I want to **support a promising Italian SME** and contribute to Italy's recovery. I have two children and I learn lessons on management from them every day.

Experience

Chief Service Officer at Datalogic S.p.A.

January 2017 – June 2022 Bologna, Italy

General manager of Services Business Unit, with full P&L responsibility. In charge of service delivery, tech support and repair programs.

Achievements: Customer Support Digitalization; Operations and Contractors right sizing, leading to increased Gross Margin (from 60% to 70% in 3 years); New Business Development (30% of 2019 revenues came from new accounts / services vs 10% in 2017).

Operations Planning and Service Director at Datalogic S.p.A.

October 2014 – December 2016- Bologna, Italy

Director of Supply Chain and Customer Service.

Achievements: Defined and implement a S&OP process, leading to 98% OTD (On Time Delivery), vs 95% in previous year; successful post M&A integration of a 20 M€ business, focusing on manufacturing and service operations.

EMEA Director of Supply Chain and Service at Culligan Italiana S.p.A.

April 2014 – September 2014, Bologna, Italy

I led the supply chain of a 70M€ complex business (B2B and B2C, private and public sectors, over 400 suppliers, make to stock and make to order).

Achievements: Implemented a new distribution model, including next day on site services, reducing costs, and improving customer experience. Spearheaded a customer satisfaction improvement initiative, focusing on dealers and generating and increase of 20% in recurring business.

Operations Director at Culligan Italiana S.p.A.

October 2011 – April 2014- Bologna, Italy

In charge of the main production site in EMEA, coordinating 70 people. I managed production, quality and safety, supply chain and warehousing.

Achievements: implemented a project management process for Key Accounts, leading to a 10pp increase in profitability.

Supply Chain Manager at Mondi Group

October 2008 - October 2011 - Bologna, Italy

Reporting to the CEO, I oversaw Supply Chain activities of a 40 M€ production plant.

Plant Procurement Manager at Fiat Auto

September 2007 - September 2008 – Lecce, Italy

In charge of all the procurement and planning activities of the CNH (Case New Holland) plant.

Project management SAP- Procurement at Ciba Specialty Chemicals (then BASF)

February 2006 - August 2007 - Basel, Switzerland

I was responsible of the global BPR (Business Process Reengineering) project for Procurement. I worked closely with country managers on change management and personnel's role mapping within the new organization. I managed budget and resources.

Logistic Manager at Ciba Specialty Chemicals (then BASF)

March 2005 - February 2006 - Pavia, Italy

Responsible for production planning, packaging, procurement, and materials management

Distribution and Supply Chain Project Manager at Heineken

November 2002 - February 2005 – Milan, Italy

Responsible for distribution and warehouse management across Italy, 180 SKU's, 5 plants.

Management Trainee at Bralima Brasseries (Heineken)

February 2002 - November 2002 - Kinshasa, Democratic Republic of Congo

I organized the distribution system: truck loads and routes, personnel shifts, and remuneration.

Management Trainee, Logistics Production Planner at Heineken Italia

January 2001 - February 2002 - Milan, Italy

Production planning and materials management (180 SKU's)

Researcher at Claudio Nutrito

January 1995 - December 2001 – Bologna, Italy

Research on marketing and management, creative thinking techniques, lateral thinking.

Intern at Accenture

April 2000 - September 2000- Milan, Italy

Internship, working on the design and implementation of an enterprise web portal.

Intern at MEMC Electronic Materials USA

June 1998 - September 1998 - Saint Louis

Internship in the R&D department, working on the analysis of a thermodynamic process.

Languages

Italian, Mother Tongue English, French Fluent Spanish, Lingala, Basic

Education

Insead: Business Strategy and Financial Performance – Executive Program

Università di Bologna

Industrial Engineer, Supply Chain, Plant Management, Economics, 1995 - 2000

Student Exchange Programs (merit based)

Ecole d'Ingénieurs, Sceaux, France : Logistiques, 1999 – 2000 University of Illinois, USA, Mechanical Engineering, 1997 – 1998